The road is rotten.
We arrive at Turkmenistan's most famous
landmark, a hole.
Darwaza, nicknamed the gateway to hell, is
a symbol of the country's immense gas
wealth.
It's been 50 years since methane emissions
have occurred due to an accident in the
digging of a mine.
And it's been 50 years since this crater
has been on fire.
It's 70 meters long, 30 meters deep.
In 1971, Soviet scientists set fire to the
crater to stop a gas leak.
They thought the fire would not last.
Today, it's still as powerful as ever.
Of course, this gas is constantly burning.
There are many toxic emissions.
We can feel it in our breath, we have a
sore throat.
But what comes out of the ground is
methane.
And Turkmenistan is one of the world's
main polluters because of methane.
It's a real ecological disaster.
Because of leaks, every year the country
emits 4.4 million tonnes of methane.
A greenhouse gas 80 times more harmful
than CO2.
But the authorities don't seem to mind.
The site has been transformed into an
attraction where meat is barbecued in the
evening.
And where a small camp with yurts has been
set up to welcome tourists.
Good evening from the middle of the
Karakum desert.
Do you know how many tourists visit this
place each year?
Each year?
Totally it's 12 000.
Yeah.
But this is a famous place so I think that
more than half of them visit this place.
But now I'm busy, I have to prepare
another two.
That's for you.
With just 12,000 tourists a year,
Turkmenistan is one of the least visited
countries in the world.
Here we are.
A small mattress and a small military
sleeping bag.
And off we go.
A peaceful night awaits us in the toxic
fumes.